# J.R. Lewis

## **SKILLS**

Have been riding horses since before I could walk. Showed Reining competitively from junior high through college, placing in the top twenty at the AQHA World Show my last two years competing as a non-pro. Have apprenticed and worked as an assistant trainer for professionals across the state in a variety of disciplines. Developed a talent for starting young horses and focused on the initial training of colts for my business.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Gillespie Ranch, Dublin - ASSISTANT TRAINER/COLT STARTER

MARCH 2023 - MAY 2023

- Primary Responsibilities focused on Colt Starting
- TunedUp/Maintained Finished ShowHorses
- Assisted in General RanchWork when needed.

## **Valentine Reining Horses, Pilot Point** — ASSISTANT TRAINER

JANUARY 2023 - MARCH 2023

- Maintained Conditioning/Training on Finished ShowHorses
- Started colts. From initial groundwork to greenbroke horses

## **Villhest Ranch, Boerne** — RANCH MANAGER

MARCH 2022 - DECEMBER 2022

- Responsible for All Ranch Maintenance and Improvements
- Supervise Employees and Contractors
- Operated Equipment
- Oversee Daily Ranch Operations

### **EDUCATION**

### **Hubbard High School** - Diploma

2006 - 2010, Hubbard, Texas

Graduated with a 4.0, National Honors Society, and many Athletic Awards/Achievements